Guide to the Palestinian Liberation Movement Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Palestinian liberation movement collection
1986-1994
MS 1701
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of posters, photographs of posters, and a photographic postcard portfolio entitled "Intifada: Occupied Territory taken by eight Italian Photographers," documenting the twenty-fifth anniversary of the Palestine National Liberation Movement, the first anniversary of the Palestine State Proclamation, the second anniversary of the Intifada, and other issues and events concerning Palestinian movements. An addition to the collection includes posters relating primarily to the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (P.F.L.P.) and similar organizations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was transferred to Manuscripts and Archives from the Near East Collection, 1995, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of posters, photographs of posters, and a photographic postcard portfolio entitled "Intifada: Occupied Territory taken by eight Italian Photographers," documenting the twenty-fifth anniversary of the Palestine National Liberation Movement, the first anniversary of the Palestine State Proclamation, the second anniversary of the Intifada, and other issues and events concerning Palestinian movements. An addition to the collection includes posters relating primarily to the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (P.F.L.P.) and similar organizations.
Intifada, 1987-1993; Fatḥ (Organization); Jabhah al-Shaʻbīyah li-Taḥrīr Filasṭīn; Munaẓẓamat al-Taḥrīr al-Filasṭīnīyah
- Original accession, Accession 1996-M-058
  - Photographs
    - General Palestinian themes (Box 1)
    - Twenty-fifth anniversary ofthe Palestine Liberation Movement (Box 1)
    - First anniversary ofthe Palestinian State Proclamation (Box 1)
    - "Second anniversary ofthe Palestinian Intifada" (Box 1)
    - "Intifada: Occupied Territory taken by eight Italian Photographers" [photographic postcard portfolio], 1990 (Box 1)
  - Posters
    Scope and Contents
    Includes posters created by the Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO) and Roots (a Palestinian youth group that was based in Washington, D.C., in the 1980s) depicting movement martyrs: Abu Jihad, Abu Muhammad, Abu al-Hawl, Abu Iyad, Khalid al-Hasan, Muhammad Ismail Abu Nafisah, Husni Abd al-Rahman al-Araj, and commemorating Land Day; PLO anniversaries; and the 1989 Intifada.
    - General (Folder 2A, Folder 1)
    - 1988 (Folder 2B)
    - 1989 (Folder 2C)
    - 1990 (Folder 2D)
    - Land Day (Folder 2E)
    - People killed during Intifada (Folder 2F)
    - Duplicates (Folder 2G)
- Additional material, Circa 1980s-1990s; Accession 2006-M-008; 2; (1 box) (Box 1)
  - Posters, primarily for Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP), Circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1)